Before we start,
let's look at what
the ML practitioner
term refers to.
Many users within
an organization
have a part to play
in the ML lifecycle.
For example, a product manager
who simply types of query to
pull necessary insights from
a data dashboard
or data warehouse.
Or a data scientist who works on
different aspects of building
and validating models.
Think also about an ML engineer
who is responsible for
the model to work
without issues to serve
end-users in a
production environment.
ML practitioner is
used to describe
all these different roles
throughout the ML lifecycle.
Now, let's look at the challenges
these ML practitioners
face when they
operationalize and
make their models
available for production.
These challenges
include managing
and keeping track
of complex details,
such as data, model
architectures, hyperparameters,
and experiments.
As for specific pinpoints,
we hear it can be
challenging to keep track
of different versions of
the models and their codes.
Different training
procedure parameters,
hyperparameter values
in each trial,
and performance metrics control
the experiments
space to advance.
In every iteration,
these practitioners
need to monitor what
changes are being made,
which ideas are being tried,
which ideas work,
and which ideas don't,
pinpoint the best
performing model when
the models are benchmarked
against each other.
The best model here refers
to the one that delivers
the ideal result for
your specific use case.
Collaborate with
data scientists,
data engineers, ML engineers,
application developers,
site reliability engineers,
business analysts and
business users in
operationalizing the ML models.
Then there's the matter
of reproducibility.
Deploying a model to
a production environment is
difficult unless it
can be reproduced.
In fact, bypassing
the reproducibility
of the model is often
discouraged or disallowed
by policies or regulations.
Reproducibility can
be a major concern
for ML practitioners because
they want to be able to rerun
the best model with a more
comprehensive parameter sweep.
When a team successfully
trained and make
some model ready for production
in a streamlined fashion,
performance, and agility
are considerably improved.
Even if there's a manual
review step in the pipeline,
automation ensures
that each job is
configured and executed
in a repeatable manner,
which reduces the
risk of errors.
Also, for a production
application,
the model needs to be updated
regularly as new data comes in.
Therefore, traceability
becomes paramount.